Hi everyone!
大家好！
Have you ever had this experience?
你是否曾經有過這樣的經歷？
You face a super big case
你面對一個超級大案子
and your brain is blank
但你的腦子一片空白
and you don't know where to start
不知道從哪裡開始
as if you are stuck.
好像被卡住了。
Today we are going to talk about
今天我們要談論
how to help your important case
如何幫助你重要的案子
get rid of all the obstacles in front of you.
消除面前的所有障礙。
But before we start,
但在我們開始之前，
let's take a look at this picture.
讓我們看看這張圖片。
Hmm, 403 Error.
嗯，403 錯誤。
Do you feel a little headache
你是否只是看著它
just by looking at this?
就感到有點頭疼？
Unable to fulfill the request
無法完成請求
The request has been blocked.
該請求已被封鎖。
Wow, does this sound
哇，這聽起來
cold enough
是否足夠冷淡
and sharp enough?
並且足夠犀利？
He is telling you
它在告訴你
Hey, this road is not going to work.
嘿，這條路行不通。
Don't even think about it.
別想都別想。
No discussion.
沒有商量。
Does this make you immediately think
這是否讓你立刻想到
that sometimes your own case
有時你自己的案子
seems to be hit by this kind of 403 error?
似乎被這種 403 錯誤擊中了？
You are clearly full of ideas
你顯然滿腦子想法
and your whole body is clean.
而且整個身體很清爽。
But there is a invisible wall
但有一堵無形的牆
that blocks you from your original place.
將你從原來的地方擋住了。
That's right.
沒錯。
So today we are going to talk about
所以今天我們要談論
the feeling of being blocked by request.
被請求阻止的感受。
Let's turn it from a cold technical error
讓我們把它從一個冷冰冰的技術錯誤
into something that we may all encounter.
變成我們都可能遇到的東西。
Hmm, the difficulty of life.
嗯，人生的困難。
Do you know?
你知道嗎？
This feeling
這種感受
is actually like your brain is suddenly cut off
實際上就像你的大腦突然被切斷
and can't connect to that so-called
無法連接到所謂的
Sensor of Inspiration.
靈感感測器。
There are obviously a lot of ideas in your brain
顯然你的腦子裡有很多想法
and half of them are running fast over there.
其中一半在那邊快速運行。
The traffic is so large that it doesn't work.
流量太大了，無法正常工作。
But you just can't see
但你就是看不到
where you're going to step next.
你下一步要往哪裡走。
This is your personal personal 403 error.
這是你個人的 403 錯誤。
But the good news is
但好消息是
just like repairing the network problem,
就像修復網路問題一樣，
we actually have a way
我們實際上有辦法
to get rid of this brain barrier.
消除這個大腦障礙。
So what's the solution?
那麼解決方案是什麼呢？
It's a strategic distribution.
這是一個策略性分配。
The strategic distribution
策略性分配
sounds a bit complicated, doesn't it?
聽起來有點複雜，對吧？
To be honest,
老實說，
it's a deep conversation
這是一場深度對話
with an AI partner
與一個 AI 夥伴
with a structure and a goal.
有著結構和目標。
The purpose of this conversation
這次對話的目的
is to help you plan and disassemble the project
是幫助你規劃和拆解項目
and distribute the tasks one by one.
並逐個分配任務。
That's right.
沒錯。
AI is the key helper
AI 是關鍵助手
that can unlock the blocked request for you.
它能為你解鎖被阻擋的請求。
Okay, let's not talk nonsense.
好吧，我們不廢話了。
Let's take a look at
讓我們看一看
a super practical three-step plan.
一個超實用的三步驟計畫。
This framework
這個框架
allows you to apply the concept we just talked about
允許你應用我們剛才談論的概念
to your own project
到你自己的項目中
and start working immediately.
並立即開始工作。
Before we start,
在我們開始之前，
you can pick one of these three types
你可以從螢幕上選擇這三種類型中的一種
from the screen
從螢幕上
and think about it.
並思考一下。
Whether it's communication, research,
無論是溝通、研究、
or some creative ideas,
還是一些創意想法，
or even learning new things,
甚至是學習新事物，
this method is all suitable.
這個方法都很適用。
The core of this plan is actually very simple.
這個計畫的核心其實非常簡單。
The first step, of course,
第一步，當然是
is to select the project you want to handle.
選擇你想要處理的專案。
The second step
第二步
is to talk to your AI partner
是與你的 AI 夥伴對話
and define the vision and goal of this project together.
並一起定義這個專案的願景和目標。
Then the most important third step
然後最重要的第三步
is to disassemble the entire project
是將整個專案分解
into small tasks one by one
逐一分成小任務
and decide how to distribute these tasks.
並決定如何分配這些任務。
Okay, now we're going to get into the whole plan.
好的，現在我們要進入整個計畫。
I think the most interesting
我認為最有趣的
and the most core part.
也是最核心的部分。
Let's take a look at
讓我們看看
how to cleverly
如何巧妙地
combine the strengths of humans
結合人類的優勢
with the abilities of AI
與 AI 的能力
to create the effect of 1 plus 1 is greater than 2.
創造 1 加 1 大於 2 的效果。
Hey, what's the key to success?
嘿，成功的關鍵是什麼？
In fact, you need to be able to clearly distinguish
實際上，你需要能夠清楚地區分
which tasks need to perform the most
哪些任務需要發揮最多
of our human observation,
我們人類的觀察力、
experience, and value judgment.
經驗和價值判斷。
And what tasks
以及哪些任務
can use AI's
能夠利用 AI 的
super-strong data analysis
超強數據分析
and content development ability
和內容開發能力
to help us accelerate.
來幫助我們加速。
Let's just use it as an example
讓我們就用它作為例子
to make it clear.
來說明清楚。
You see,
你看，
to launch a simple topic
推出一個簡單的主題
requires your personal knowledge and passion, right?
需要你個人的知識和熱情，對吧？
So, of course, it's up to humans,
所以，當然，是由人類來做，
that is, yourself.
也就是你自己。
What about the latest statistics?
最新的統計資料呢？
This kind of hard work that needs to be quickly collected, analyzed, and organized
這種需要快速收集、分析和整理的繁重工作
is definitely half the work of AI.
絕對是 AI 的工作的一半。
As for the content of the video you post,
至於你發佈的影片內容，
this is the part that is most suitable for cooperation.
這是最適合合作的部分。
You can connect the structure with AI one by one.
你可以逐一將結構與 AI 連接起來。
But the most important thing
但最重要的事情
is to define the core message of this report,
是定義這份報告的核心訊息，
which is where the soul is.
那就是靈魂所在。
This matter concerns your values and aspirations.
這涉及你的價值觀和抱負。
In the end, it's still up to you
最後，還是要由你
to decide the case by humans.
來決定由人類判決。
There is a very, very important point here.
這裡有一個非常、非常重要的點。
Everyone must remember
每個人都必須記住
that the whole process is not
整個過程不是
your one-sided instruction to AI,
你對 AI 的單方面指令，
not to treat it as a tool person.
不要把它當成工具人。
You should treat it as a partner
你應該把它當作夥伴
and have a sincere conversation with it.
與它進行真誠的對話。
What does it mean?
這是什麼意思呢？
It means you have to keep asking questions
這意味著你必須不斷提出問題
and challenge the answers it gives you.
並質疑它給你的答案。
Then, in this kind of back-and-forth discussion,
然後，在這種來回的討論中，
you can stimulate the inspirations and movements
你可以激發那些靈感和想法
that you may never think of
這些是你獨自思考時
when you are thinking about it alone.
可能永遠想不到的。
Okay, before you start using this method
好的，在你開始用這個方法
with a very excited mind,
滿懷興奮之前，
let's pause for a moment
讓我們暫停一下
and spend a little time to reflect on the whole process
花一點時間反思整個過程
and the impact it may have.
以及它可能帶來的影響。
You can ask yourself first,
你可以先問自己，
in the conversation you had with AI just now,
在你剛才與 AI 的對話中，
did any of the movements that you didn't expect
有沒有你意想不到的想法
or did any of the aha moments
或有沒有任何「啊哈」時刻
make you suddenly blink?
突然讓你眼前一亮？
Next, we have to be more practical and think about it.
接下來，我們必須更實際地思考一下。
What do you think will be the most difficult part
你認為在實際執行這個分配計畫時
when you actually implement this distribution plan?
最困難的部分會是什麼？
Be prepared first.
事先做好準備。
When you really encounter it,
當你真正遇到它時，
you won't be in a hurry.
你就不會慌張了。
Finally, you can think further.
最後，你可以進一步思考。
What additional information do you think you need
你認為你還需要什麼額外信息
or what new skills do you need
或者你需要什麼新的技能
to make your future smarter
讓你的未來更加智慧
and more effective in distributing tasks to AI?
並更有效地將任務分配給 AI？
Remember, this is a new ability
記住，這是一項新的能力
that requires us to constantly learn and progress.
需要我們不斷學習和進步。
Okay, I've given you the method, framework, and mentality.
好的，我已經給了你方法、框架和心態。
Now it's time to ask yourself
現在是時候問你自己
the most important question.
最重要的問題。
In your current job,
在你目前的工作中，
the 403 error that made you stuck for the longest time,
讓你卡住最久的 403 錯誤，
have you prepared to solve it
你是否已準備好一起解決它
all together?
呢？